

Meysam HASHEMI Senior Research Flow



Welcome to my home page



+33 (0)695573212



Meysam.hashemi@gmail.com Meysam.hashemi@univ-amu.fr



27 blvd. Jean Moulin 13005, Marseille, France





French, Iranian

LANGUAGES

English, French, Persian

Google Scholar



Citations h-index i10-index	301 10 10	228 10 10
	_	120
		90
		60
1.		30
2016 2017	2018 2019 2020 2021 2022 2023	0





References

Viktor JIRSA Axel HUTT

(viktor.jirsa@univ-amu.fr) (axel.hutt@inria.fr) A. VALIZADEH (valizade@iasbs.ac.ir)

Profile

I develop and adapt biologically- and physics-informed AI/ML tools for flexible and efficient parameter estimation using Frequentist and Bayesian approaches. I have extensive experience (>12 years) in working with computational models at single spiking neuron, neural populational (mean-field), and whole-brain levels, both analytically and numerically, to improve diagnostics, interventions and therapies for brain-related medicine, digital health and drug research (General Anaesthesia, Epilepsy, Parkinson, Alzheimer, Aging, AUD, and other brain diseases).

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Science: Physics, solid state | 2004-2008 KHU, Tehran, Iran.
- Master of Science: Physics, soft condensed matter | 2008-2012 IASBS, Zanjan, Iran.

Thesis: Effect of duration of synaptic activity on spike rate of a Hodgkin-Huxley neuron with delayed feedback.

PhD: Computer science | 2012-2016

Université de Lorraine, Nancy, France

Thesis: Analytical and numerical studies of thalamo-cortical neural population models during general anesthesia.

Postdoctoral: AI/ML for digital brain twins | 2016-2023 Aix-Marseille université, Marseille, France

Project: State-of-the-art Bayesian inference on the virtual brain models for brain diseases; Deep neural density estimators for simulated-based inference and adaptive Monte Carlo for principled and automatic statistical estimation.



WORK EXPERIENCE

- PhD. researcher: INRIA Grand-Est, Nancy, France | 2012-2016
- RHU researcher: INS, EPINOV, Marseille, France | 2016-2023
- Engineer researcher: SATT Sud-Est, Marseille, France | 2017-2018
- Data scientist: EBRAINS, Human Brain Project (HBP) | 2018-2023



SKILLS

- Bayesian inference on Brain Signals: (S)EEG/MEG, fMRI, for Clinical Trials.
- Oscillations, Spiking and Neural-Mass models, Pharmacometrics, Stimulation.
- Probabilistic AI/ML, Dynamical system, DCM, Differential equations (ODEs/DDEs).
- Monte Carlo algorithms, Variational and Simulation-based Inference, Optimization.
- Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Matlab, C++, Git, Slurm, high-performance computing.
- PPLs: Stan, PyMC3, NumPyro, Edvard, Turing, scikit-learn, and The Virtual Brain.



ACTIVITIES

- >35 Publications including Lancet Neurology, Science Medicine, Science Advances, Nature Computational Biology, NeuroImage, Neuroinformatics, PLOS CB, ...
- Multiple patents with current use in national clinical trials and best tech Innov. HBP).
- (co-)Supervising master and PhD students, teaching, grant-writing, and workshops.